<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS-GY-6613 Artificial Intelligence - Spring 2020 on CS-GY-6613 Spring 2020</title>
    <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CS-GY-6613 Artificial Intelligence - Spring 2020 on CS-GY-6613 Spring 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Syllabus The course schedule below highlights our journey to understand the multiple subsystems and how they can be connected together to create compelling but, currently, domain specific forms of intelligence.
Books Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach, by Stuart Russell, 3rd edition, 2010 and also here.
The publisher is about to release the 4th edition (2020) of this classic. We will be monitoring availability in bookstores but it does not seem likely this edition to appear on time for the Spring 2020 class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ai-intro/ai-pipelines/ai-pipelines-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ai-intro/ai-pipelines/ai-pipelines-slides/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Workflow</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/development-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/development-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Workflow Steps Although the ML project checklist provided in Appendix B of Garon&amp;rsquo;s book is extensive (we will go through this list in the lecture as we go through your first ML application) for now focus on the eight steps as shown below.
Steps in workflow (from here)
 As discussed the data pipeline is responsible for providing the training datasets if the aim is to train (or retrain) a model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Tensorflow</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/tensorflow-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/tensorflow-introduction/</guid>
      <description>In this lecture we will cover slides #1 - #28 as shown below. The slides are from CS 20: Tensorflow for Deep Learning Research and despite the title are appropriate for Tensorflow beginners. Slides beyond #28 will be selectively consulted when we go over gradients and backpropagation.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Python (Numpy/Scipy and Pandas)</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/numpy-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/numpy-pandas/</guid>
      <description>Standard Python Below is a list of recommended courses you can attend to. We will go over briefly basic Python in this lecture. The tutorials below are self contained and can remind you the basics.
 CodeAcademy Data Science Path. Take Python modules 4-10. This course contains Numpy and Panda intro as well.
 Kaggle Python Course
 Google Python Class This is a bit dated as it covers Python 2, but it is still highly regarded as Python 3 and 2 have few differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization and Stochastic Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-math/optimization/optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-math/optimization/optimization/</guid>
      <description> In this lecture we will go over concepts from Ian Goodfellow&amp;rsquo;s chapter 4 below. Stochastic gradient descent is treated also in section 5.9.
Ian Goodfellow&amp;rsquo;s Chapter 4  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Information Theory Basics</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-math/probability/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-math/probability/probability/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapters From Ian Goodfellow&amp;rsquo;s book: 
We will go through the main points during the lecture and treat also MacKay&amp;rsquo;s book (Chapter 2) that is also instructive and a much better in introducing probability concepts. If you are a visual learner, the visual information theory blog post is also a good starting point.
Key Concepts to understand Probability The pictures below are from MacKays book and despite their conceptual simplicity they hide many questions that we will go over the lecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/projects/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/projects/project-3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Netflix Prize and Singular Value Decomposition</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-math/netflix/netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-math/netflix/netflix/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The following are based on the winning submission paper as well as their subsequent publication.
The Netflix Prize was an open competition for the best collaborative filtering algorithm to predict user ratings for films, based on previous ratings without any other information about the users or films, i.e. without the users or the films being identified except by numbers assigned for the contest.
The competition was held by Netflix, an online DVD-rental and video streaming service, and was open to anyone who is neither connected with Netflix (current and former employees, agents, close relatives of Netflix employees, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zillow App</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/zillow-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/lectures/ml-frameworks/zillow-app/</guid>
      <description>The Zillow app is based on the end to end machine learning example in Chapter 2 of Geron&amp;rsquo;s book. We can go through this end to end example during a recitation.
 Key Questions  Is the dataset appropriate for training?   Any unexpected ranges, any range heterogeneity, any clipping? Do we face long-tails? What options do we have to glean the data?
  What will happen if we remove the following line from the split_train_set function?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Programming Environment</title>
      <link>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/projects/env/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pantelis.github.io/cs-gy-6613-spring-2020/docs/projects/env/</guid>
      <description>Your Programming Environment Starting Jupyter in Google Colab The runtime performance will greatly improve for some projects using the free GPU resources provided by Google Colab. In this course we will make use of these facilities - the good news is that you have an account in Google Colab as most of you have a google account. If not go ahead and create one to be able to login into Google colab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>